准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
中世纪历险记
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
赶紧的  派大星
Hurry, Patrick
角斗赛要开始了
It's almost time for the joust
我跟着你呢  海绵宝宝
Right behind you, SpongeBob
中世纪时刻
欢迎来到中世纪时刻
Welcome to Medieval Moments
你们只需再走上二十巫师步
You're just 20 wizard's paces away
即可体验剑术巫术  及恶劣卫生条件
from swords, sorcery and bad hygiene
请往这边走
Right this way, please
不好意思  兄台
Excuse me, my good man
吾认为汝应说  此处请
I believe thou meant to say, "Righteth this wayeth"
以后再说吧
Someday
今天就免了
but not today
羊肉好不好吃  派大星
How's that mutton, Patrick?
我看羊肉味道好极了
Me thinks it's mutton-tastic
莫里
Morrie
你应该要宣布角斗赛开始的
You're supposed to announce the jousting tournament
晚上好  各位中世纪时刻的观众们
Good evening, uh, fair patrons of Medieval Moments
依照皇家法令  我们将要求两名观众
By royal decree, we ask that two audience members
过来上台参加那什么
come forth and participate in the, uh
皇家角斗赛
the royal jousting
看这边
Over here
快选  选我们
Pick up, pick us
看这边
Over here
选我们
Pick us
好吧
All right
看来粉海星跟黄海绵
It appears that
the pink starfish and the yellow sponge
就是我们今晚的幸运参与者了
are our lucky contestants tonight
万岁
Hooray
激不激动啊  派大星
Isn't this exciting, Patrick?
居然马上就能近距离观赏角斗赛了
To think, we'll be watching the joust this close up
你们不是来观赏角斗赛的
You won't be watching the joust
是来参加角斗赛的
You're in the joust
派大星  你会骑海马吗
Pat, do you know how to ride a sea horse?
不知道
Nuh-uh
海马先生
Mr. Sea Horse, sir
你会不会对新手温柔点啊
you're gentle on beginners, aren't you?
海绵宝宝  救命
SpongeBob, help
取他首级
Take his head off
现在好像不适合
I don't suppose now would be a good time
请求上厕所
to ask for a bathroom break
派大星
Patrick
真高兴都结束了
I'm glad that's over
快看
Look
餐厅的员工过来救我们了
Some employees from the restaurant came to help us
逮捕这些叛徒
Arrest these traitors
罪名是从天而降施法
for committing the act of witchcraft
by falling from the sky
整得真是比真实还真实
They really go that extra mile for authenticity
向骑士同伴们致意
Salutations, fellow knights
不要吵  异端
Silence, heathen
我懂了
I get the point
晚安  小姐们
Nighty-night, ladies
老老实实坐牢吧
You'll have many more in here
派大星  这些道具好逼真
Gee, Pat, these props sure are convincing
这什么破烂乐器
Blast this confounded instrument
要是我一直都吹不好
If I never learn to play with ease
那就让我
may mine own
曾曾曾曾曾曾曾孙
great, great, great, great, great, great, great grandson
受十倍诅咒
be cursed tenfold
章鱼哥  你在这干什么
Squidward, what are you doing here?
汝同吾言乎
Does thou talketh to me?
真好笑  章鱼哥
Good one, Squidward
汝同吾言乎
"Does thou talketh to me?"
勿哂之  先生
Scoff not, young squire
汝认错了
Thou has mistaken me for another
我乃章鱼兄  国王之弄臣
I am Squidly, the king's royal fool
至少我被贬入狱之前还是
Or at least I was until I royally messed up
干什么被贬
What did you do?
你们看好了
I'll show you
我尝为国王心爱的弄臣
I was the king's favorite fool
将欢笑带到世间
I made merry mirth and laughter
讲了个冷笑话  国王中风倒下
Then I told one bad joke and the king had a stroke
于是我被挂于房椽
Now I hang from ye ol' rafter
我得在这干什么才能有羊肉吃
What does a guy have to do
to get some mutton around here?
可饿死我了
I'm starving
想得真是美
Don't hold thy breath
十二世纪咱还能有东西吃就算走运了
We'll be lucky if we get fed again by the 12th century
这边人表演得还挺认真的
They sure take their role-playing seriously around here
什么声音
What's that?
邪恶巫师之龙来临
The evil wizard's dragon is here
四方百姓惊声尖叫
See the townsfolk scream with fear
四方百姓慌忙奔走
See the townsfolk try to run
一切显然不欢不乐
I can tell this won't be fun
恶龙欲要焚烧一切
The dragon will torch everything
山谷万物尽数消灭
Everything in the valley
医院学校与养老院
Hospitals, schools, retirement homes
养老院
保龄球馆
连保龄球馆也不放过
And even Ye Olde Bowling Alley
别碰保龄球馆
Not the bowling alley
骑士  弄臣
Knights, jesters
恶龙  中世纪保龄球馆
dragons, medieval bowling alleys
十二世纪
12th century
还不明白吗  派大星
Don't you see, Patrick?
我们真的穿越到中世纪了
We really are in medieval times
完了
Oh, no
我家水龙头好像忘关了
I think I left the water running at home
国王要跟你们两个说个话
The king wants a word with you two
等等
Wait
要走就要带章鱼兄
We don't leave without Squidly
凭什么要带
Why should I take him?
因为
Because, um
章鱼兄给国王想了些好歌
Squidly has thought of
some brilliant songs for the king
必须得让国王听
and he just has to hear them
对不对  章鱼兄
Isn't that right, Squidly?
绝对是对的
Absolutely
章鱼兄
Squidly, uh
还是见着国王再吹好了
maybe you should wait for the king to hear that
随便了
Suit thine self
汝不知艺之失也
Thou does not knowest what thou art missing
苦也
Woe is me
怎么办
What to do
父王  汝缘何而泣
Father, what art thou going on about now?
还是同样那件事  亲爱的女儿
Just the same old thing, dear daughter
是那个可恨的痞老巫
It's that wretched wizard, Planktonimor
他阴险狡诈的恶龙毁了我大半个王国
His insidious dragons destroyed half me kingdom
将来就不会有国民来交税了
Soon there will be no citizens to tax
我最好的骑士们就没一个能打败他的
Not one of me best knights has been able to defeat him
父王  别忘了您的高血压
Father, remember your blood pressure
您应该不想再来一次水蛭疗法了吧
You wouldn't want another leech treatment, would you?
陛下
Your Highness
地下城主把您要召见的囚犯带来了
The Dungeon Master
has brought the prisoners you asked for
那就不要傻站着  带他们进来
Well, don't just stand there, send them in
遵命  陛下
Sure thing, Your Highness
蟹老板
Hey, Mr. Krabs
你胆敢以那样的语气叫我  混账
How dare you bark at me in that tone, knave?
我是这个王国最受敬畏的统治者
I am the feared ruler of this kingdom
对我讲话要尊重一点
and will be addressed as such
抱歉
Sorry
还有你们为什么把这弄臣带回我正殿
And why have you brought this fool
back into me throne room?
请陛下大发慈悲
If your majesty may be so kind
我有首歌可以回答您所有的问题
I think I have a song
that will answer all your questions
那好那好
All right, all right
不过这回是你最后的机会  弄臣
But this is your last chance, fool
多谢国王陛下
Thank you, Sire, thank you
不会让您失望的
You won't be disappointed
国王请您听我唱
Oh, hear me, King, for I must sing
尔可谓样样精通
How you are the greatest at everything
放纵恶龙烧全城
Like letting a dragon burn down our city
美景已然不再成
A horrible sight that wasn't pretty
汝之过错皆可憎
'Twas all your fault and 'tis a pity
尔甚恶难辞其咎
You were bad, you are to blame
绞汝尊首以耻之
Now hang your kingly head in shame
王甚恶难辞其咎
The king is bad, the king's to blame
绞其尊首以耻之
He hangs his kingly head in shame
来人
Guards
把这些造谣诽谤的送上断头台
Send these slanderers to the guillotine
等等  你不明白
Wait, you don't understand
我们不属于这里
We're not from here
因为你们是巫师
That's because you're witches
奉痞老巫的命要来灭掉我
who were sent by Planktonimor to destroy me
不是的
No
我们是穿越来的
We're time travelers
救救我  派大星
Help me out here, Patrick
我不清楚有没有什么话可以帮你找补
I'm not sure there's anything I can add at this point
我受够这些儿戏了
Okay, I'm through playing around
来人
Guards
别  等等
No, wait
拜托不要
No, please
父王  您必须要饶了他们
Father, you must spare them
汝仍记预言否
Has thou forgotten of the prophecy?
什么预言
What prophecy?
就在您头顶正上方的那个
The one right above your head
那玩意在上面多久了
How long has that been there?
预言说
The story tells
有两个从天而降的勇敢骑士
of two brave knights who fall from the sky
会被国王派遣  让可怜的小镇摆脱
and are sent by the king to rid the lamenting town
受控于独眼巫师的恶龙
of the evil dragon controlled by the one-eyed wizard
父王  您就不明白吗
Father, don't you get it?
那就是他们
It's them
这些陌生人过来拯救我们了
These strangers have come to rescue us
跟预言讲的一模一样
Like in the prophecy
你胆敢玷污我的王宫  恶魔
How dare you defile my house, demon?
珍珍公主
Princess Pearl
珍珍  我来了
I'm coming, Pearl
准备好受死吧  禽兽
Prepare to meet thy maker, foul beast
一切都要结束了  派大星
Well, I-I guess this is it, Patrick
我看也是
I guess so
我会想你的  海绵宝宝
I'm going to miss you, SpongeBob
我也会想你的  兄弟
I'll miss you, too, buddy
父王  救命
Daddy, help
珍珍
Pearl
就没人能阻止这乱局的蔓延吗
Can no one stop this madness?
你们
You
你们两个
you two
接受我的歉意
My apologies
最崇高
most noble
最尊敬的
and valued
战士
warriors
这就是所谓的皇家礼遇吧
I guess this is what you call the royal treatment
愿海神保佑你们
May Neptune grant you safety
披荆斩棘  平安抵达邪恶巫师城堡
on your perilous journey to the evil wizard's castle
那里从来没有人能活着逃出来
from which no one has escaped alive
路上有很多艰难险阻吗
We're going on a perilous journey?
不过当然了
But of course
你们可是救世主
You're the chosen ones
这什么东西
What's this?
失踪的一块预言
A lost piece of the prophecy?
我猜猜
Let me guess--
又是赞扬我们英雄气概的吗
more praise for our heroic stature?
其实  上面画着我应该把你们踢出去
Actually, it says I was supposed to kick you out of here
不必多说了  陛下
Say no more, Your Majesty
我们英勇骑士特别英勇
Us manly knights are so manly
自个踢自个出去就行了
we kick ourselves out of places
踢吧  派大星
Come on, Patrick
小心了  大恶人
Look out, trouble
不用他们陪了
Well, so much for their company
我思索再三  你得跟他们一起去
On second thought, you better go with them
他们可以拿你寻欢作乐
They could use the entertainment
随你的便
Have it your way
祝你们好运  陌生人
Good luck, strange ones
虽然我们确实被预言选中了
I know we're a prophecy and all
可是手无寸铁应该没法阻止恶龙
but I don't think
we can stop the dragon with our bare hands
没错
Yeah
所以说得整点铁
We need some gloves
可能那边的铁匠
Perhaps yonder blacksmith
可以给你们作战提供装备
could provide some arms for your battle
铁匠
终于啊
At last
有位辛勤的劳动者
An honest man of the soil
看我轻松跟这野蛮本地人打成一片
Observe as I effortlessly
commingle with this brutish native
你好  铁匠
Greetings, Iron Man
我是海绵宝宝爵士  来自裤头
I am Sir SpongeBob, of Bikini
村
Bottom
我老早就告诉过你们了
I told you people before
我有钱自然会交租
I'll have the rent when I have it
我们只是要来买武器的
We just wanted to buy some armor
那你怎么不早说
Why didn't you just say that?
我正好有适合你的东西
I've got just the thing for you
真是太棒了
This is awesome
海绵宝宝  出来下
Hey, SpongeBob, get out here
海绵宝宝  你看起来可真是妙
SpongeBob, you look incredible
现在奉上防卫武器
And now, for the piece de resistance
你的剑  勇士
Your sword, brave knight
以阳极电镀龙皮为材料亲手锻造而成
Hand-forged from anodized dragon's skin
这武器绝对可以配上你们这样的勇士
It is truly a weapon worthy of a knight of your stature
好像有点重了
A little heavy, isn't it?
这伤得要缝好几针了
That's going to need some stitches
我找下还有什么
Let me see what else I got
非常不幸  我手上的轻型武器
Unfortunately, all I have in the way of light weaponry
只有这把水母网
is this jellyfish net
真是完美
That's perfect
我们还有很长的路得走
We doth have a long journey ahead of us
幸好我给咱打包了干粮
It's a good thing I packed us a lunch
也就是美味的蟹黄堡
of delicious krabby patties
传说中的预言就这
This be the legendary prophecy?
电话簿
笑死我了
That be-eth rich
简直是在侮辱我  这样就不好笑了
T'would almost insult me, were it not so funny
痞老巫  汝属实过分自大矣
Planktonimor, thou art cocky
and overly-confident with thyself
相信我吧  凯伦
Trusteth in me, Karen
我知道我是在干什么
I doth knowest what I am doing
到这来  小家伙
Come hither, boy
把我的战书下放给蟹国王陛下
Deliver my demands unto his majesty, King Krabs
站住
Halt
来者何人
Who goes there?
我没看错吧
Doth mine eyes betray me?
是邪恶的黑暗骑士
'Tis the nefarious Dark Knight
黑暗骑士  我来求饶
Oh, Dark Knight, spare us please
别砍掉头  膝盖莫搞
Don't cut off our heads or boil our knees
带离他们
Pray, take these two
让我远走
And let me go free
我会给你送来
And I will give to thee some
奶酪
cheese
黑暗骑士
Dark Knight?
我再问一个问题  然后就肢解你们
I asketh once more, before I rip thee limb from limb
报上名来
Reveal thyself
我是海绵宝宝  这位是派大星
I am SpongeBob, and this is Patrick
我们是派来
We've been spent
从痞老巫手里救出珍珍公主的
to rescue Princess Pearl from Planktonimor
汝欲过此路
If thou wisheth to get across
必须过我这关
thou willst have to get through me
中世纪珊迪
Medieval Sandy
我知道怎么个对付法
I know how to handle this
整点空手道就行了
with a little karate
老天啊
By the hammer of Odin
这居然是我从来没见过的全新招式
this be a new fighting style mine eyes have not yet seen
我特坏
I am bad
好耶
Oh, yeah
汝欲辱我
Doth thou tryeth to insult me?
必先自取其辱
Thou whilst drink from the fountain of shame
听见没  派大星
Do you hear that, Patrick?
早说她会松鼠似的突过来
I told you she zings like a squir
厉害  中世纪珊迪
Good one, medieval Sandy
可是你能对付得了我的怒火之脚吗
But can you handle my feet of fury?
想来摩擦摩擦一下吗
Wouldst thou like a little rubdown?
你打败我了  黄骑士
You have bested me, yellow knight
打得真是快准狠  勇士海绵
Strike quick and true, noble sponge
我听不懂你刚刚说的话
I don't understand a word you just said
中世纪珊迪
Medieval Sandy?
你的样子不太对
You don't look so good
珊迪
Sandy?
Sandy
咋
What?
派大星  起效了
Patrick, it's working
再来一遍
Do it again
你饶了我一命  好心的勇士海绵
Thou hast spared me, kind and noble sponge
作为对你们的回报
and to thee, I owe a debt of gratitude
我将跟随你们一同踏上征程
for I will follow you in your quest
打败痞老巫
to defeat Planktonimor
顺便跟你学空手道
and learn a trifle of that karate
空手道
Karate
陛下  陛下
Your majesty, your majesty
有份卷轴要寄给您
A scroll hath arrived for thee
汝须交出城池
"Thou must hand over thy village
及宝座
and thy throne?
否则汝之女将坠入岩浆大釜
Or thy daughter shall be dipped in a cauldron of lava?"
珍珍
Pearl
那是公主的惨叫声
That be the shriek of the fair princess
倾听公主  塔上惨叫
Hark, the princess, she screams from the tower
呼声表明  其命难保
By the sound of her shrieks, this is her final hour
紧要关头到了
Then time be of the essence
还记得计划吗
Doth we all remember thy plan?
不记得
No
我说的是记得
I mean yes
记得
Yes
我就这么说的
That's what I said
记得
Yes
快点前进吧
Then let us forge on
给我让开  野蛮人
Make way, heathens
黑暗骑士要过去
Dark Knight coming through
请表明你的来意  黑暗骑士
State thy business, Dark Knight
这些土包子图谋
These village idiots are conspirators
要对痞老巫大人造反
against Master Planktonimor
我需要知道痞老巫大人
and I needeth to know which form of torture
想怎么折磨这些可怜的蠢蛋
thy master wishes upon these wretched fools
可不可以五马分尸他们
Do I have their limbs tied to horses
and swiftly yanked apart--
还是一根一根拔掉眼睫毛
Or pluck each individual eyelash, one by one
让他们连愿望都许不了
taking away their every single last eyelash wish?
不要
No
不要不要不要
No, no, no
很好  黑暗骑士
Very well, Dark Knight
准许进入
Entrance be granted
不要不要不要
No, no, no
站住
Halt
拔根睫毛许个愿
Make a wish
你这办法真不错  海绵宝宝爵士
Goodsome thinking, Sir SpongeBob
表现得跟个穿尿布的小屁孩似的
posing as a frightened wee babe in ye old diapers
他们想不信都不行
did make it most believable
所以你觉得我们骗到他们了吗
Yeah, you think we fooled them?
珍珍公主
Princess Pearl
我必须得让预言成真
I must fulfill the prophecy
你去给派大星跟那个卖傻的松绑
while you untie Patrick and the royal doofus
那叫弄臣
That be royal fool
撑住  珍珍
Hang on, Pearl
我们来救你了
We're coming to rescue you
你马上就自由了
Freedom is at hand
我们马上就来
We're a-coming
就快到了
Almost there
我的海神王啊
Oh, dear Neptune
国王的城池马上就是我的了
Soon, the king's village will be mine
我的了
Mine
放了她
Unhand her
恶魔
fiend
预言就要实现了
The prophecy is nigh
我们是来救你的  珍珍
We're here to rescue you, Pearl
我能来杯水喝吗
Could I get a glass of water?
苏打水
要苏打水还是纯净水
Sparkling or regular?
纯净水
都不给
Psyche-eth
你整个就是裤头郡最讨人嫌的巫师
You truly are the nastiest wizard
in all of Bikini Bottomshire
准备好战败吧
Prepare to be vanquished
放马过来吧  混账
Bring it on-eth, knave
怎么
What the
哪去了
where?
我没看到你  你小死了
I didn't see you, you're so tiny
好痒
That tickles
法力真小
Tiny powers
我没事
I be-eth okay
好啊
Yes
快电他们
Sicceth them, boy
可能来首柔和短歌可以让你静下来
Perhaps a soothing limerick will calm thee
从前有条龙  英俊又聪慧
There once was a dragon so handsome and smart
它心胸宽广  让我自由而归
He let me go free, for he had a big heart
大家都好会批评
Everyone be-eth a critic
别过来
No, no, no, no
你们已经是死路一条了  小白痴
Dead end for you, simpletons
等一下
Wait a second
未来的人肯定不会相信这回事的
The boys back home will never believe this
我就是在这都不信这回事
I'm right here, and I don't believe it
不要
No
大限还是到了  派大星
Well, I guess this is it, Pat
确实
Yeah
现在咱可以吃蟹黄堡了吧
Can we eat those krabby patties now?
可以啊  兄弟
Sure, buddy
派大星快看
Patrick, look
它在吃蟹黄堡
he's eating the krabby patty
不要啊
No, no, no
太可怕了
The horror, the horror
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
这是大好事
it's a good thing
真的吗
It is?
当然真的了
Sure it is
听它呼噜叫的
Just listen to him purr
可太爱吃蟹黄堡了
He loves that krabby patty
到底是在搞什么鬼
Forsooth, what be-eth going on here?
快消灭他们
Destroy them
给我马上就灭
Do it now, or so help me
我会很乐意再给你做
I'd be more than happy to make you some more
好吃的蟹黄堡的
of those delicious krabby patties
该死
Curses
你们赢了
You win
都让条道
Make way
国王的英雄们要过去
Thy king's heroes cometh through
听钟声响起
Hark, ring the bell
皆大欢喜
'Tis all ended well
恶龙已被征服  公主完成归途
The dragon is vanquished, the princess returned
我们中只有一两个被烧得很惨
And only a few of us got badly burned
上菜了
Order up
不知道可不可以卖这些
I doth wonder if I couldst sell these
蟹黄堡
krabby patties
难听死了
That horrible noise
让他别吹了
Make it stop
孩子  你没事吧
Hey, kid, are you okay?
你们刚摔得很重
That was some fall you had
可真不该激怒那只海马
I guess I shouldn't have agitated that sea horse
刚刚的梦还精彩吧  派大星
That was some dream, huh, Patrick?
派大星
Patrick?
这话还是跟章鱼兄讲吧
Try telling that to Squidly